{
    "id": "e805d0b1f006474fa78c46a233196231",
    "title": "Intermediate Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It is time we .......................",
            "description": "After it’s time, we use a past tense to refer to the present or future.",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "have left",
                "left"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a97f56098ce4410a8b5d69e81ef23700"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………….. them a couple of times when I was in London.",
            "description": "We use the simple past with expressions referring to the past.",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "have visited",
                "had visited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f007f3149dbd4fceb7f1440e04e2c32d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………….. him before.",
            "description": "When there is no reference to a definite point of time in the past, we use a present perfect tense to talk about past events.",
            "answers": [
                "never met",
                "have never met",
                "never meet"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dd0adf9247724c89963ea24ba35f6620"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………….. it if I were you.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "would buy",
                "would have bought",
                "will buy"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d4a645eefec24dbc903a4d382e6e2f63"
        },
        {
            "question": "It’s a long time ……………. I went there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "for",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "37d57d07b89744e985872b2420bd0185"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ……………… today.",
            "description": "Better is the comparative form of good. We cannot say ‘more good’.",
            "answers": [
                "much better",
                "much more better",
                "much more good",
                "much good"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "492185c9482d489a88ba8cd333c73b1e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I was surprised to see that ……………. James was there.",
            "description": "We use ‘even’ to talk about surprising extremes. Even if and even though are conjunctions.",
            "answers": [
                "even",
                "even if",
                "even though"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "12a13ed8c48c4723873d6b6be0ae1d70"
        },
        {
            "question": "I bought the watch ……………….. it was very expensive.",
            "description": "Even though is the emphatic form of ‘though’. It has a past reference.",
            "answers": [
                "even though",
                "even if",
                "even as"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b2ba558c652b448d840a903e36e59c92"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will buy that watch …………………. it is very expensive.",
            "description": "Even if has a future reference.",
            "answers": [
                "even if",
                "even though",
                "even"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7640f99cec6d44c79589cd756d9a0936"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………. the phone and quickly dialed the number.",
            "description": "To reach for something is to stretch your arms to grab it.",
            "answers": [
                "reached",
                "reached for",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "65906b89c52c4679b3b74a2c1fc2d111"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first time I …………….. him was last year.",
            "description": "We use the simple past with definite past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "meet",
                "have met"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e724fd932773486b9ad7c07aab862d19"
        },
        {
            "question": "Take the certificates with you just in case they ……………… you a job.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "offer",
                "will offer",
                "offered"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "abe795746f004be3bbcb1d6a1cbb65d9"
        }
    ]
}